Guide to the Southcomb Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Sermons, 1788-1872; Series II; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  - John Ladaveze Hamilton Southcomb (1817-1886)
    - 256. 3 Mar 1852, Matt. 4:7, On Our Lord's Temptation, No. 2 257. 10 Mar 1852, Matt. 4:8-10, On Our Lord's Temptation, No. 3 258. 11 Apr 1852, 1 Cor. 15:20-22. Easter Sunday 259. 30 May 1852, John 14:16-17, Whitsunday (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - 260. 27 Jun 1852, 2 Chro. 7:15-16, For the Church Building Society 261. 25 Jul 1852, Rev. 20:12-13, Funeral 262. 15 Aug 1852, Matt. 12:36 263. 12 Sep 1852, Rom. 13:12-14, Fair Sunday (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - 264. 26 Dec 1852, Acts 7:59-60, The End of the Year and St. Stephen's Day 265. 16 Oct 1853, Matt. 5:19, For National Society 266. 26 Mar 1854, Gen. 45:8, 1st Less.: PM for 4th Sunday in Lent 267. 4 Jun 1854, Hab. 2:14, For S.P.G.F.P. particular occasion (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - 268. 6 Aug 1854, Heb. 13:14, Farewell 269. 26 Nov 1854, 2 Chro. 6:34-35, Written and Preached on Behalf of the Widows and Orphans of our Troops who may fall in the Campaign now going against Russia. 270. 25 Dec 1854, Luke 2:14, For Christmas Day 271. 21 Mar 1855, Jer. 9:23-24, Written for, and preached on the day appointed for general Humiliation on going to war with Russia. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - 272. 21 Mar 1855, Dan. 9:16, Written for, & preached on ---, being (Wednesday) a day set apart for solemn National Fast and Humiliation on acct. of Crimean Army's Losses 273. 11 Nov 1855, 1 Chro. 22:19, For the Society for building and enlarging Churches 274. 18 May 1856, Acts 8:17, On Confirmation 275. 7 Oct 1857, Jer. 51:13, Written on occasion of Fast in consequence of the military outbreak in India (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - 276. 9 Nov 1862, 1 Cor. 12:26, For the distresed Manufacturers--1862: Owing to the Scarcity of Cotton from the Yankee Civil War. Including 4 Nov 1862 edition of "The Evening Standard" of London and single columns cut fromthe 5 Nov and 7 Nov 1862 editions. Articles on distress in Cotton disctricts, esp. Manchester and Lancashire. 277. 26 Jul 1863, 1 Kings 13:15 278. 9 Oct 1864, Matt. 13:32-34, For Soc. Prop. Gospel 279. 27 Feb 1872, 2 Chro. 32:24, Preached on Thanksgiving Day for the Prince of Wales' recovery from Typhus Fever. (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Diaries of John Ladaveze Hamilton Southcomb (1817-1886), 1835-1877; Series III; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series III contains eight diaries by John Ladaveze Hamilton Southcomb, including one entitled "Walking Tours of Cornwall," September 16 to September 26, 1846. These diaries cover his daily activities from August 10, 1835 to August 27, 1852 and the seven years from January 1870 to February 1877.
  - 10 Aug 1835 - 11 Nov 1835 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 11 Nov 1835 - 27 Nov 1836 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1 Jan 1841 - 31 Dec 1845 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1 Jan 1846 - 28 Feb 1849 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 16 Sep 1846 - 26 Sep 1846--Walking Tour of Cornwall (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1 Mar 1849 - 4 Feb 1851 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 5 Feb 1851 - 27 Aug 1852 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 1 Jan 1870 - 1 Feb 1877 (Box 7, Folder 8)